Pinocchio 3000 is a animation, family, fantasy
film directed by Daniel Robichaud.
This is the story of a little robot known as Pinocchio 3000
whose greatest wish is to become a real boy.
The year is 3000.
Geppetto, with the help of his faithful assistant, Spencer the cyber penguin, and by the
holographic fairy Cyberina, creates Pinocchio, a prototype superrobot equipped for emotions.
But before he can be given a heart and become a real boy, Cyberina insists
that Pinocchio learn the difference between right and wrong.
Scamboli (voice), played by Malcolm McDowell.
Pinocchio (voice), played by Sonja Ball.
Geppetto (voice), played by Howard Ryshpan.
Cyberina (voice), played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Spencer (voice), played by Howie Mandel.
Jake (voice), played by Bobby Edner.
Pinocchio 3000 (or P3K – Pinocchio 3000) is a 2003 animated science fantasy film
directed by Daniel Robichaud and distributed by Christal Films.
A Canadian-French-Spanish co-production, the film is a futuristic science fiction interpretation of the classic 1883 novel The Adventures of Pinocchio by Carlo
Collodi, with Pinocchio (voiced by Sonja Ball) being a robot brought to life by tapping into a city's power surge, rather than a puppet animated by magic.
The film centers on the basic story of Pinocchio attempting to fit into living with humans in the town of
Scamboville, a futuristic city constantly under development under the reign of its namesake, Mayor Scamboli.
The film explores themes of child abuse, flying car, concert, computer, police.
The tone is thought_provoking.